<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
    <title>jeremy&#x27;s neglected blog</title>
    <description>jeremy&#x27;s neglected blog</description>
    <link>http://jeremyosborne.com</link>
    
    <item>
        <title>Hearthstone: An actual free-to-play game (plus my Paladin Deck Build)</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/hearthstone_beta.html</link>
        <description>Hearthstone, from Blizzard Entertainment is a digital, collectible card game that is currently in open beta (as in anyone reading this article can play). Being promoted as a free-to-play game, I wanted to see whether that was a euphamism for "first hit is free" or whether Hearthstone might genuinely be free-to-play-and-enjoy while not costing anything other than the player's time.After a few days of playing it, in my opinion this game can be enjoyed at the free level, even with some obvious caveats. I enjoy the game and will keep playing as I have spare time here and there. Perhaps...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Procedural World Generation</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/procedural_world_generation.html</link>
        <description>I have been working on making a video game, and wanted an excuse to do some procedural world generation. Procedural generation of some kind is a part of a lot of the games that I like to play, and it seems to be what the cool kids are doing nowadays. This is a collection of links on procedural programming, and how I'm working through my ignorance to better understand it.I'm never ignorant while I'm still ignorant. That's probably why, absently mindedly, I spent ~2 hours searching the internet for "procedural world generation" and not finding the tools or the code...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Organic coding experiment conclusion</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/organic_coding_conclusion.html</link>
        <description>Watching my normal habits rarely leads me to new conclusions in life, but the path traveled can be rewarding. In previous articles (here, and here) I took a look at how I write code when, other than daydreaming, I do zero design up front. What did I do? How did I work? The results are not surprising.I had a spring break of sorts over the last week, and took the time to revisit my current understanding of JavaScript in the browser within the world of a 2d canvas. I explored another game library called gamejs in the hopes of making...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>ffmpeg recipes</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/ffmpeg_recipes.html</link>
        <description>In my recent attempts to use open source software for video conversions and editing, I have settled on using ffmpeg. The learning curve for ffmpeg was a bit steep, compounded by the fact that the newer versions of ffmpeg use slightly different options than what a lot of past, pageranked blog posts have documented.Because of how useful and powerful ffmpeg has turned out to be, I'm starting a page of ffmpeg recipes. If you are interested in the ffmpeg recipes, please bookmark the page referenced in the ffmpeg recipes link. I'll be posting new recipes there, not here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Semantics of Versioning</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/semantic_versioning.html</link>
        <description>I don't always play video games, but when I do, I like to try indie games and open source games. I have gotten into the Let's Play phenomenon on youtube and, after some bad starts (video and audio encoding woes, and a lot of forced education about video and audio in general) with the good old game Warlords, I aimed to do a Let's Play of an open source video game. Open source projects can always use free publicity.The open source game that I first chose, and was going to record, will remain nameless in this article. It has a...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Organic Design and Video Games</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/organic_design_and_video_games.html</link>
        <description>I love it when experiments take on a life of their own. I had previously indulged some video game silliness in a small amount of spare time. I also took the time to document what goes through my mind when I write code, in particular when I code organically, which is what I call "stream of consciousness" but for programmers.Finding a bit more time to continue the experiment, I've put together three more steps of the small game that I'm calling shootdown. Below is my documentation of my internal dialog as I move forward, along with a snapshot of the...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Falling (back) in love with Node.js</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/falling_in_love_with_nodejs.html</link>
        <description>A few years ago when I first found out about Node.js (hereafter referred to as node), I thought it was the absolute coolest thing ever. "Cool!" I thought, I can dump Django and PHP and my reliance on those server side engineers. <ignorance class='bliss'>I can do it all myself!</ignorance> Honeymoons, thankfully, don't last. My first impression of node quickly turned into despair at having to code everything myself that I was used to getting for free in other web frameworks. Whether those thoughts were accurate at the time, they were my thoughts, and lacking a node therapy/support group I moved...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>JavaScript and Video Games</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/javascript_and_videogames.html</link>
        <description>I decided to mess around with making video games in JavaScript. I have no real time to do so, but video games make me happy. Plus it's a good chance to use myself as a lab rat for self-imposed timeboxing and agile and all those other words that the cool kids are using these days to increasne effectiveness.I picked up a game engine that I have previously used called jsGameSoup because I am familiar with it. It's small, light weight, modular, and has an interface approach that I like. A small bit of time into this experiment, I became aware...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Electronic Legacy of Lucy Teh Chicken</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/the_electronic_legacy_of_lucy_teh_chicken.html</link>
        <description>About a year and a half ago we decided to get chickens. It's our version of pets, as we like cute animals but we're not very keen on creatures that do nothing more than eat, sleep, and lick themselves. One of the chickens was the runt of the group, and we named her Lucy. The others were Xena, Lucretia, and Deanna, or rather the evil step sisters. We read a lot of stuff about chickens and learned about pecking orders. The pecking order of a chicken herd makes the Indian caste system sound like equality. We had a bit of...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Weighted Data</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/weighted_data.html</link>
        <description>Sometime in July of 2010, I stood on the scale and the scale told me, in block digital letters, that I weighed 179 lbs. In the grand scheme of things, that's not such a bad weight. Yet for the months prior to that time I had made all of the changes that I thought I needed to make to keep my weight in the 160s. I was biking to and from work most days a week, and averaging about 10 miles minimum, 7 days a week. I had started doing yoga with my wife, and was just beginning to hit...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Things I learned from Movies</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/things_i_learned_from_movies.html</link>
        <description>I have pretty simple hobbies, and one of them is movie watching. I love movies, all kinds: good ones, bad ones, super awesome B-Movies with high budgets for special effects and no budgets for acting, the inverse of the just referenced type of movie. Most movies really have nothing to offer other than a few hours of hedonistic pleasure and the pure joy of being entertained. Every now and then, there's something that I learn from a movie that nothing else in life—not school, not my parents, not my wife, not my friends—taught me. Below are my favorites:Ferris Bueller's Day...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Reusable Code</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/reusable_code.html</link>
        <description>A lot has happened since last Wednesday, which will be a story for another time, a long time in the future, which I'll probably use to frighten the grandkids.Since then I've been doing a lot of coding. When I don't code at work, I follow only a few set of rules:That gives me a sandbox to play in, with appropriate boundaries. Inside of this giant playground, I just code and try things out. Most things I do nowadays are strictly JavaScript (and CSS and HTML), and that, too, provides a pretty large playground within a playground.Like my writing, most of...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Crazy, not insane</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/crazy_not_insane.html</link>
        <description>In regards to a decision that I recently made, my wife told me that:Given that my favorite book ever is Catch 22, I'm very much okay with this assessment of my psychology. I've recently wondered if the sane were not crazy, and if [at least a few] of the crazy were not sane. I'm really not sure anymore.All I know is I'm about to be off on another adventure. We'll see how this one turns out compared to all of the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why I Voted No on Measure J</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/why_i_voted_no_on_measure_j.html</link>
        <description>Tomorrow Santa Clara, California opens it's polls for the California June, 2010 Primaries. Santa Clara City, the city I live in, has been pushing, and pushing, and pushing Measure J. There's some substance to Measure J, but the simple version is:A yes vote on Measure J means we, the citizens, allow the building a stadium near the that the San Francisco 49ers will play their games in.Will they become the Santa Clara 49ers? No, that would be pretty stupid. Essentially, my view of this measure, being someone who could give a rats ass about football, is the equivalent of voting...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Skeletons</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/skeletons.html</link>
        <description>In Dungeons and Dragons, skeletons are described as:Magically animated, undead monsters enchanted by powerful magic-users or clerics of evil alignment.In real life, they're a euphemism, at least in English, symbolizing hidden secrets that everyone has; hence the term skeletons in the closet.EVERYONE HAS THEM. I LIKE TO YELL IN MY BLOG. Steve Carell sez: "I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE YELLING ABOUT!" But Einstein says:Stupid people will paraphrase everything I say 80 years from now. BLAH BLAH BLAH.Skeletons + Einstein = Relativity. And like BAM! It makes sense why all senators who are against gay marriage are secretly having massive amounts...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Honesty, it&#x27;s a worthy bitch</title>
        <link>http://jeremyosborne.com/posts/honesty_its_a_worthy_bitch.html</link>
        <description>I've never been very good at being fully honest. Around 2005, after I had a few quarter-life crises, I decided that I'd start down the long path of discovering what it meant to be honest.A little over 5 years down that path, I think I know less than when I started, but I think I found the punchline of being honest:Once you start down the honesty path, you have to keep going.This has been the simplest, yet hardest piece for me to grasp. What does this look like in real life?[Random Person]: How are you doing?You realize they are talking...</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
</rss>
